<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Brightvale Human</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="race-brightvale-human.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/community-elements/elements-reddit/master/reddit/reddit-unearthed-arcana/blazing-dawn-players-companion/race-astran.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Brightvale Human" type="Race" source="Brightvale" id="ID_BRIGHTVALE_RACE_HUMAN">
        <description>
            <h4>Men of the Fields.</h4>
            <p>Physical: </p>
            <p>Culture: </p>
            <h4>Human Traits</h4>
            <p>
                <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Your Strength score increases by 2, and your Charisma score increases by 1.<br />
                <span class="feature">Ploughshare Community.</span> Proficient with the Insight skill.<br />
                <span class="feature">The Guild System.</span> Most humans train as apprentices for some time in their life, either with their parents or being sent abroad. You can choose one tool to be proficient in. You can make two skills you are proficient in an expertise.<br />
                <span class="feature">Guild Education.</span> You may choose two 1st level Artificer spells you may cast as rituals.<br />
                <span class="feature">Earth Affinity.</span> Mold Earth cantrip & Goodberry.<br />
            </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="names" type="male">.</set>
            <set name="names" type="female">Antlia, Aquila, Aries, Caelum, Cepheus, Circinus, Crux, Dorado, Equuleus, Fornax, Horologium, Hydrus, Leo, Libra, Monoceros, Orion, Pavo, Sculptor, Serpens, Tucana, Virgo, Volans.</set>
            <set name="names" type="clan"></set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>
            <set name="height" modifier="2d10">6’8"</set>
            <set name="weight" modifier="2d4">120 lb.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>description</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="wisdom" value="2" />
            <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_RADIANT" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_BDPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_MYSTICAL_MENTOR" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_BDPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARLIGHT_NAVIGATOR" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_BDPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_WIELDER_OF_LIGHT_AND_FLAME" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_BDPC_LANGUAGE_ASTRAN" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Mystical Mentor" type="Racial Trait" source="Blazing Dawn Player’s Companion" id="ID_BDPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_MYSTICAL_MENTOR">
        <description>
            <p>With your touch, you can temporarily transfer some of your skill and knowledge to another creature. As an action, you can touch a willing creature, and select a skill that you are proficient in. If the target isn’t already proficient in that skill, it becomes proficient in it for the next 8 hours.</p>
            <p>Once you use this trait, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action">
            <description>You can touch a willing creature, and select a skill that you are proficient in. If the target isn’t already proficient in that skill, it becomes proficient in it for the next 8 hours.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Starlight Navigator" type="Racial Trait" source="Blazing Dawn Player’s Companion" id="ID_BDPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARLIGHT_NAVIGATOR">
        <description>
            <p>Your memory is exceptionally good when it comes to the locations of all the stars that dot the night sky. As long as you can see the night sky, you know which way is north, and you have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks made to avoid becoming lost.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As long as you can see the night sky, you know which way is north, and you have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks made to avoid becoming lost.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Wielder of Light and Flame" type="Racial Trait" source="Blazing Dawn Player’s Companion" id="ID_BDPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_WIELDER_OF_LIGHT_AND_FLAME">
        <description>
            <p>As a child of the stars, you can call upon innate magic granted to you by your astral heritage. You know the light and control flames cantrips. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast faerie fire with this trait, and starting at 5th level, you can also cast flaming sphere with it as a 2nd level spell. Once you cast a spell with this trait, you can’t cast it again until you finish a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast light and control flames at will.</description>
            <description level="3">You can cast light and control flames at will. You can cast faerie fire once per long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells (save DC {{astran-spell:dc}}).</description>
            <description level="5">You can cast light and control flames at will. You can cast faerie fire and flaming sphere (as a 2nd level spell) once per long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells (save DC {{astran-spell:dc}}).</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CONTROL_FLAMES" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAMING_SPHERE" level="5" />
            <stat name="astran-spell:dc" value="8" />
            <stat name="astran-spell:dc" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="astran-spell:dc" value="wisdom:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Astran" type="Language" source="Blazing Dawn Player’s Companion" id="ID_BDPC_LANGUAGE_ASTRAN">
        <description>
            <p>Typically spoken by Astrans.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="exotic">true</set>
            <set name="speakers">Astran</set>
            <set name="script">Alien Script</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>
